MUHAMMED SHAN

muhammedshan0512@gmail.com

+918606288429

PROFILE

I am a hands-on, highly competent software engineer with 6.2 years of experience in designing, programming software in .Net platforms. I have worked on numerous projects from concept to completion. I take pride in coding to consistently high standards and regularly refresh my skills to ensure and keep up with ongoing developments.

PREVIOUS PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer - October 2020 To Present

Thinkpalm Technologies Pvt. Ltd, ERNAKULAM, KERALA

- Implement various features in ApprovPay Project and resolve issues in existing project.
- Migrate database from MSSQL to MYSQL
- Developing new/additional features in the product.

Senior Software Engineer - June 2019 To October 20

UST Global Pvt. Ltd, ERNAKULAM, KERALA

- Implement OKTA SSO on various applications related to health care insurance.
- Modernize Existing Applications
- Developing new/additional features in the product.

Software Engineer - November 2017 To June 2019 Nest Information Technologies Pvt. Ltd, ERNAKULAM, KERALA

- Developed various modules of Banking system in C#.net Web based applications
- Developing new/additional features in the product.
- Gathering information from the client personnel for new features.

Software Engineer - July 2015 To November 2017 DATAMATE INFOSOLUTION Pvt. Ltd, ERNAKULAM, KERALA

- Developed various modules of hospital management system in VB.net Web based applications
- Developing new/additional features in the product. .
- Gathering information from the client personnel for new features.
- Creating SRS of the developed forms.

Software Engineer Trainee - May 2013 To November 2013 DACON TECHNOLOGIES, ERNAKULAM, KERALA

- Develop Web based applications in C#.
- · Research, design and implement best practice solutions to new problems
- Contribute to the ongoing improvement of software practices within the business

EDUCATION

COURSE	PERIOD OF STUDY	INSTITUTION	BOARD/ UNIVERSITY	MARKS (%)
MBA(operations)	2015-2019	Indira Gandhi National Open university	Indira Gandhi National Open university	55
B.TECH (Computer Science &Engineering)	2009-2013	Ilahia College of Engineering &Technology, Muvattupuzha.	Mahatma Gandhi University, Kottayam	65
HSE	2007-2009	Govt.Model.H.S.S Cheruvattoor	Kerala State Higher Secondary Board	79
SSLC	2006-2007	Govt.Model.H.S.S Cheruvattoor	Kerala State Board	69

PROJECT DETAILS

• ApprovPay Classic

- ApprovPay allows their clients to pay employees worldwide by eliminating manual processes from global payroll.
- Implement Database Migration from MSSQL Server to MySQL.
- Implement New feature in Approvpay project and resolve issues in existing project.
- **Technology used:** ASP.NET CORE 3.1,ASP.NET MVC,C#, , SQL Server 2016,EntityFrameWork Core, Visual Studio 2019,WebApi,POSTMAN, ,Swagger
- **Development Methodologies :** Agile Methodolgy

• OKTA SSO Implementation

- Implement OKTA Single Sign on Various Applications in Health Insurance Projects. Also Modernize existing Application into well modernized applications.
- Technology used: ASP.NET CORE, ASP.NET MVC, C#, JavaScript, Jquery, SQL Server 2016, EntityFrameWork, Visual Studio 2017, 2019, WebApi, POSTMAN, Angular
- **Development Methodologies :** Agile Methodolgy

• UAEFTS Product

- The objective of the product is to develop a web-based reliable and flexible system with the capability to integrate the FTS transactions between Central Bank UAE and Bank. This system will give the GUI for generating and process the FTS system files using a defined workflow of approvals.
- **Technology used**: C#, ASP.NET 3.5, 4, JavaScript, SQL Server 2008, Visual Studio 2008, 2012, 2013, 2017, WebService, WCF.
- Development Methodologies: Waterfall Model

Hospital Management System

- Modules related to Hospital Management.(Vb.net,Oracle)
- Handling Doctor Desk, Nursing Station, Casualty, MRD modules
- Create New Module for Discharged patients.
- Handling Dynamic Reports and Dynamic forms
- Create Master for web forms and generate its report.
- Technology used: VB.net, ASP.NET 3.5, 4, JQuery, Oracle, Visual Studio 2013, WebService, Ajax., HTML5, CSS3.
- Development Methodologies: Waterfall Model.

• Library management Software

- Develop Modules Related to Library management Software(C#, sql server2008).
- Technology used: C#.net, ASP.NET 3.5, JavaScript, Ajax, Visual Studio 2013, WebService, Ajax., HTML5, CSS3.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating System: Linux, Windows XP, 7 & 8

Language : ASP.NET.CORE,ASP.NET MVC,ASP.NET,C#,VB.net,ADO.Net,Ajax,

Internet Technology : JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5,CSS3,Angular

Databases : MS SQL Server 2016,2005, 2008,2014 MySQL, MS Access, Oracle. Frame Work : .NET CORE 3.1,NET 4.5, .NET 4.0, .NET 3.5,EntityFrameWork

IDE : Microsoft visual Studio 2010,2012, 2013,2017,2019

PERSONAL PROFILE

Father's Name : Basheer MA

Age, Date of birth : 29, 5th December 1991

Gender : Male Nationality : Indian

Address : Mulambel House, Mulavoor P O, Muvattupuzha

Language known : English, Hindi and Malayalam

REFERENCE

• Mr.Manu Sasidharan Nair, Project Manager

UST Global Pvt Ltd,Infoaprk,Kakkanad,Cochin

- · Mr.Shibin K N,Team Lead Nest Information Technologies, Idachira, Kakkanad
- · Mr. Vibin Kumar, Team Lead

Datamate Info Solution, CSEZ, Kakanad, Ernakulam

· Mr. Sajeesh Varghese, HR

Datamate Info Solution, CSEZ, Kakanad, Ernakulam

DECLARATION

I declare that the information furnished above are true & correct to the best of my knowledge.

ERNAKULAM KERALA, INDIA

MUHAMMED SHAN MB